Um, all right, let's get to some of
these ah questions slides questions.
Will China provide Iran with
intelligence and continue to sell them
weapons? Absolutely, yes.
Um, Bahrain is buzzing with revolution
talk. Is it likely that a full-scale
uprising will occur? What would be the
consequences?
>> That is a very important question. So,
historically, Bahrain had been between
2/3 and 3/4 Shia Muslim. The royal
family is Sunni Muslim. When I was
there, I was there during what is now
called
>> situation. Yeah, I I was living there
during what was then called
the Intifada. It became now known as the
first Intifada. And and it was
freaking hideous, let me tell you. So,
what the what the Bahraini royal family
did in the intervening 30 years, I was
living there 30 years ago, is they
imported Syrians,
gave them Syrians are mostly Sunni
Muslims, gave them Bahraini citizenship,
and then started naturalizing Indian and
Pakistani Muslims, Sunni Muslims. So,
now it's closer to 50/50. But even
though it's closer to 50/50, the Shia
the Sunnis still have money, the Shia
are still poor, so there is always a
threat of an uprising in Bahrain. Uh,
now that the war has started, is there
any way to end it with peace in the
region without an increase in terror
attacks?
Not the not the second one.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, what will the impact be if Congress
does take Trump's war powers away? I
don't think doesn't look, John, like
that's going to happen, right? We're
going to see a vote,
um, but there's enough
there's even though there's some
conservatives who are,
you know, I think Thomas Massie,
Rand Paul, people like that who are
going to vote for the war powers
resolution, but there's also going to be
the John Fettermans and other Democrats
in name only who are going to cross the
other way. So it'll probably look kind
of like a normal vote in Congress that
Democrats try to get through that fails.
Yeah, and if it's written as a
resolution, a sense of the Congress
resolution,
it's not going to have any any teeth or
authority anyway, if it's done as
as a you know, bill being passed into
law, the president's going to veto it.
Um
let's see.
Uh
Over the past year, several current
Israeli former Israeli officials have
pointed at Turkey as the next strategic
threat to Israel. God, what a change.
They used to be buddies. Yeah, they used
to be close buddies, which is one of the
reasons why the
Greeks and the Palestinians were so
close.
Um
Yeah,
you and I should explore this more
deeply at some point, but
but let's say that let's say that the
Israelis are successful in Iran. Mhm.
And and the Iranian leadership is
removed from from power, there's no need
to worry anymore about uh
about an Iranian nuclear program,
but the Israelis are always looking to
attack the next guy. Yeah, well, this is
that's the rest of this question from
our anonymous question here.
Does Turkey constitute a meaningful
military, diplomatic, or economic threat
to Israel? Not only in terms of
capabilities, I would say yes in terms
of capabilities, but also in terms of oh
my god, it just
uh it just
um it just it just it moved forward. I'm
sorry. Anyway,
>> Oh, that's okay. you get the idea. Yeah,
um diplomatically, yes. I I do believe
diplomatically the Israelis have their
hands full with the Turks, but that's
life. Maybe the Israelis should
try to to start getting along with
people.
Um militarily, economically, no.
No, the the the Turks aren't going to
invade Israel.
No. No. No. Yeah, I don't think they
Yeah. Um have you seen that Israelis are
going to advance troops into southern
Lebanon? They already have.
>> They did this
>> Greater Israel coming true. Although
they do that all the time, so it's hard
to say whether this is
>> There's this like 20-mi no-man's-land
uh along the border. Yeah. Yeah.
Um okay. Thank you uh
sorry. Um
Do we think Hezbollah's intervention
was a smart move for them? I mean, it it
does feel a little bit like Syria's
>> They have nothing to lose. But remember
remember martyrdom is something to be
aspired to. Right.
Um is there a big John big big fan of
the content you produce? I'm thanking
you. I want to ask is there a reason why
the UAE and Dubai is being
disproportionately targeted compared to
other Emirates in the country uh other
Gulf countries be by the count of
missiles intercepted. Other question is
that reports are showing UAE and Qatar
running out of THAAD
Yeah, so the reports uh from last night
were that the UAE would be out of THAAD
missiles in 7 days and the Qataris would
be out of them in 4 days and we can't
resupply them quickly enough. So this is
a problem. I think that the reason why
the UAE has been so disproportionately
targeted is that the UAE has been at the
forefront of the attacks against the
Houthis. Mhm. And um you know, despite
the fact that Dubai is is home to
thousands of Iranians and Iranian
businesses, I think the Iranian
government just wants to bloody the
Emiratis' noses as best they can.
Um what do you make of Marco Rubio and
Mike Johnson's suggestions that we
attacked well, we talked about this
because Israel was going to attack Iran.
Um what could possibly be the PR
strategy of such statements from such
pro-war and pro-Israel leaders.
It's really
it is baffling. It's bad PR. I mean, I'm
interested in in crisis management. I
mean, they knew they were going to do
this, right? For at least months. So,
why did they why do they not know how to
spin this? John, why is the president
still not speaking to the American
people?
You know, when he announced the the
attack, the start of the attack, he did
it
at 2:00 in the morning Mhm.
on Truth Social.
He did not address the American people.
He did not stand at the podium
in the East Room of the White House and
and make an announcement that
essentially we're at war.
He did it on Truth Social. And you're
right, he's only been going between
Washington and Mar-a-Lago, back and
forth. He has not begun crisscrossing
the country to explain why he decided to
send young American men and women
uh into battle and put their lives at
risk. He owes that
Well, I mean to the American people.
>> is I mean, the only thing I can think
of, John, is that the reason that there
we haven't seen a primetime Oval Office
address to the nation is he wants to do
this as kind of a side project. He
doesn't want it to become a defining
feature of his presidency, right?
>> Right. But but you can't it can't not
be. Want to support the show with style?
Go to dprogram.live
and check out our merch. That's
dprogram.live
or check out the description below.
Thanks for watching. Um the Balint TCC,
thank you very much for
the Hungarian forints, 4,000. I don't
have no idea how much that's worth. I'd
like to think it's a king's ransom, but
I suspect it's not. Anyway, do you guys
think that the news of 50% of Iran's
missile launching capabilities have been
taken out is true. If not, what do you
think the true figure is? Iran's missile
capabilities?
>> Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's I mean, that's what the
Pentagon is reporting. The Pentagon is
saying that we've destroyed all these
these missile launchers. I saw I saw a
report yesterday saying that 50% of
Iran's missile launchers have been
destroyed, but
the Iranians can still take deliveries
from Russia and China through the north.
And if the Russians have any idea what's
good for them, they're going to try to
get back to us for for Ukraine by
continuing to send um surface-to-air
missiles and missile launchers to the
Iranians. I would I would too, big time.
Um
LOL, thanks for the five bucks. Saudi
analysts say that that Israel attacked
their Aramco oil refinery, not Iran. Is
this another Israeli false flag? What
other false flags should we expect?
Uh speaking of false flags, on the other
side of that, Iran was accused uh by
right-wingers of attacking that school
themselves. Yeah, so stupid.
>> didn't happen. I had a friend tell me
today that he uh does not wish to speak
with me any longer because he posted
he's he's very very religious, and he
posted this thing on Facebook saying
that there are millions of people in the
streets in uh Iran, and that they're all
secretly Christian, and now a Christian
Iran's going to turn into a Christian
nation, and I and I wrote literally not
one single word of this is true.
>> [laughter]
>> And he says, "Oh, because you're the
expert." And I said, uh
"Yeah,
>> [laughter]
>> Ridiculous. Um Johanna, thanks for the
$4.99. I'm in the process of enlisting
as infantry in the army. What are the
chances that we ever use boots on the
ground in this in this war? 48 hours ago
I would have said we're not going to do
that because it's going to go very
quickly. And today I'm going to say it's
probably a 50/50 prospect because even
after the president said repeatedly we
are not going to set send boots on the
ground. Um yesterday morning Pete
Hegseth the Secretary of Defense said,
"Well, not so fast." And then the
president refused to reiterate his
earlier position that we won't send
boots on the ground.
I think there's a chance. I do, too. I
mean, I don't know if it's quite at 50%
but we're we're moving toward that
direction.
Magnus Coranis, thanks for the 50
Norwegian krona.
Why did Iran bomb all the Gulf
countries? We did address this so we
should just quickly though.
How would the Gulf countries react to
this when the Gulf countries aren't the
biggest fans of Israel? The Gulf
countries, I mean, I was just there in
the Gulf and we talked about this. They
would have they would have very
nervously just sat the whole thing out,
right? This is between the Americans
the Americans, the Israelis, and the
Iranians. But you know, when you're
blowing up hotels in Dubai or the
airport the civilian airport in Manama
and in Kuwait and you're bombing of all
people the the peace-loving Omanis who
have been trying to broker peace between
the two sides, okay, then you've made a
lot of enemies that you really didn't
need to make.